

Curriculum Vitae for Max Akira Endo Kokubun

Personal information

Address: Waldemars Hage 3 E-mail: max@xal.no

0175 Oslo Phone: +47 922 98 573

Born: 24.01.1986 Nationality: Brazilian

Summary

In essence, I am a problem-solver who relies on my scientific knowledge and experience in academia. I have a PhD in Aerospace Engineering, from the National Institute for Space Research (INPE, 2014) and before joining Expert Analytics I held two postdoctoral positions: one in Applied Mathematics, at the National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IMPA, 2014-2016), and one in Chemistry/Applied Mathematics, at the University of Bergen (UiB, 2016-2019). My role in these projects was to develop mathematical models, and its associated numerical solvers, describing experimentally-obtained results. Thus, I have an expertise in understanding real-world problems/data and translating them into a mathematical framework.

I worked in close collaboration with researchers from different backgrounds (physicists, engineers, mathematicians, experimentalist chemists, etc) and international institutions (Norway, Brazil, USA, Netherlands, Sweden, Belgium, UK). Therefore, I have excellent communication skills and can easily connect with both technical and non-technical audiences.

Technical skills

Frameworks Scipy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Keras, scikit-learn

Languages Matlab, Python, Fortran, Octave

Tools openFOAM, COMSOL, Mathematica, FEniCS, gmsh, Latex

Education

| 2011 - 2014 | PhD in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Rese- |
|-------------|---|
| | arch, Brazil. "Theoretical Study of Diffusion Flames Originated from |
| | the Burning of Heavy Liquid Fuels in Low Porosity Media (In-Situ |
| | Combustion)" |
| 2009 - 2011 | Master in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Re- |
| | search, Brazil. "Analytical Analysis of Liquid Fuel Combustion Estab- |
| | lished in a Low-Porosity Medium" |
| 2004 - 2008 | Bachelor in Physics. Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil. |

Professional experience

| 2013 - 2014 | Visiting Scholar. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA |
|-------------|---|
| 2014 - 2016 | Postdoctoral Fellow. National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathe- |
| | matics, Brazil |
| 2016 - 2019 | Postdoctoral Fellow. University of Bergen, Norway |
| 2020 | Consultant. Expert Analytics, Norway |

Languages

English Fluent
Norwegian Good
Portuguese Native
Spanish Good

Personal skills

| Analytical | I have a facility in understanding complex problems in an organized |
|---------------|--|
| thinking | matter, breaking it down into smaler, easier to understand pieces. |
| Communication | I am considered an excellent communicator, specifically when it comes |
| | to simplify very technical topics to the broader audience. |
| Problem | I like solving real-world problems by analysing them through my scien- |
| solving | tific background. |
| Team work | I enjoy being part of a team when solving problems. My experience in |
| | research was always guided by collaborative work, absorbing knowledge |
| | from more experienced researchers and guiding younger researchers. |

Some interests and hobbies

| Personal | Traveling, Hiking, Sports (football, swimming, rollerblading, tennis), |
|------------|--|
| | Music |
| Scientific | Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Data Science, Fluid Mechanics, |

Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD), Porous media, Enhanced Oil

Recovery

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Experimentally-based modelling of colloid transport in multiphase

porous media (EPOCH)

Period 2016-2019

Role Postdoctoral Fellow Staffing 8 Researchers

Volume 100

Description This project was funded by Equinor and it aimed at developing mathe-

matical models and numerical solvers for the problem of polymer particles transport in oil-water flow in porous media. The models we developed were based on experimentally-obtained results for enhan-

ced oil recovery.

Tools openFOAM, Matlab, MRST, COMSOL

Activity Mathematical modelling and analysis of medium-temperature oxida-

tion (MTO) of multicomponent oil flow in porous media

Period 2014-2016

Role Postdoctoral Fellow Staffing 4 Researchers

Volume 100

Description Development of mathematical models and numerical solvers for the

problem of reactive multiphase flow of a multicomponent oil in porous media. This project was part of IMPA's strategy to tackle industry-relevant problems by the use of high-level mathematical and numerical tools. Our theoretical results were compared with experimental results

from a collaborative research team at TU Delft.

Tools Mathematica, COMSOL, Matlab